campingandcaravanningclub.co.uk 2017-11-24

# Privacy Policy - The Camping and Caravanning Club

**This is the main Privacy Policy for The Camping and Caravanning Club and the following services, websites and applications provided by us:**

[Camping and Caravanning Club](http://campingandcaravanningclub.co.uk/ "CCC") (including booking and membership websites)  
SiteSeeker App (Apple and Android)  
Camping & Caravanning Magazine App (Apple)  
Out & About App (Apple and Android) 

At The Camping and Caravanning Club we collect different types of information about people who visit our websites (Paid Members of The Camping and Caravanning Club and Non-Members) and use our applications for three main reasons:

  1. To provide personalised services unique to individual members/users.
  2. To help us to monitor and improve the services we offer.
  3. If we have permission from the member/user, to market services to them via the channels listed below.

### **Our Services:**

  * Membership
  * Campsite Bookings (UK, European and Worldwide)
  * Insurance and Breakdown and Recovery
  * Publishing

### Our principles

We do our best to protect and respect your privacy. You should only receive marketing messages from us if you have agreed to do so. We use a combination of offline and online activity. Our marketing channels include:

  * Emails
  * Postal communications
  * Live Calls
  * Social media channels – Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Google+, Instagram, Pinterest
  * Targeted online behavioural advertising (See Cookie Policy for more information)

If we are working with any third party partners and you provide us with any data, there will be the option for you to select if you want to receive marketing information.  

We may use the above marketing channels to contact you with information or questions about your membership, your booking(s), or reviews for example, with reminders and updates.  
We collect and use details only if we have your permission or we have sensible business reasons for doing so, for example we need to collect your address to manage your membership subscription and/or any bookings you have made with us.

**What information do we collect?**

We collect information on you:

  * When you register or become a member of The Camping and Caravanning Club
  * When you use any of our websites (See our Cookie Policy)
  * Through cookies (See our Cookie Policy)
  * If you choose to reveal information (Name) in reviews
  * When you enter promotions and competitions
  * When you make a booking

When providing any of the services detailed above under ‘Our Services’ we may collect extra information, such as your date of birth, this is so we can tailor our marketing communications to you. 

### Membership

The minimum information we need when joining the Club as a member is your full name, email address, address, and a password. We ask you these questions so we can personalise your membership and make the information you receive from us more relevant providing you have opted in to receive marketing communications. 

### Marketing Communications

After you have joined the Club or made a booking with us, we may send you marketing communications via post or email that we think will be of interest to you. At the point of collection and at any time you can decide not to receive these messages. We are able to track when these messages are opened and which links contained in the emails you choose to use. This allows us to see what information is of interest to you and to tailor future messages accordingly (See Cookie Policy for more information). 

### Servicing Messages

If you are a member, we also use postal and email messages to service your membership, these include renewal notifications, reminders and voting instructions. If you have selected to be an ‘Online Member’ all of our communications with you will be done via email, except for renewal notifications which will be via post.

If you have opted out of our marketing post and/or email communication, or have previously unsubscribed from our emails, you will still receive servicing messages as we have to let you know about them as part of your membership. 

### Use of children's data

Upon joining the Club as a member, we collect and store a small amount of personal information about children. This information is voluntary during the joining process and consists of name and year of birth. This allows us to send you relevant messages, for example letting you know about camping offers during the school holidays. 

### Updating your personal information

We offer a 'My details' page, where you can update your personal information at any time. You can get to this page from most pages on the website – simply login to the ‘Membership Area’ and go to ‘Your Account’. 

If you’d like to change your marketing preferences in relation to all of our marketing channels then please [send us an email](mailto:info@thefriendlyclub.co.uk) or call the **Contact Centre on 024 7647 5442** and we will update our records accordingly.

### Bookings

When you make a booking with the Club or on any of our other websites, we may send you postal or email communications we think might be of interest you. We are able to track when email messages are opened and which links contained in the emails you use. This allows us to see what information is of interest to you and helps us to tailor future messages (Please see Cookie Policy). At the time of collection of this information you can opt out of receiving these communications. You can also, at any time, be removed from receiving these messages and we will remove you from our database. You can either do this by using the unsubscribe link in the email you have received or by [emailing us](mailto:info@thefriendlyclub.co.uk), by writing to The Camping and Caravanning Club, Greenfields House, Westwood Way, Coventry, CV4 8JH, or by calling our Contact Centre on 024 7647 5442. If you are not a member of the Club then when making a booking over the phone the advisor will also ask if you would like to receive marketing communications from us. 

### How do we use data?

The Club will use the information you provide to us in order to: 

  * Investigate and resolve any problems with any services supplied in the event of you making a complaint
  * Improve the content of our web pages (see Cookie Policy)
  * Market products and services to you which we think you will be interested in

### Who we share data with?

We will not share your personal information with any other 3rd party partners for marketing purposes unless you have given us your express permission. For example we may run a competition and the provider of the prize may like to also send promotional messages to you. At the point of entering the competition you will be given the option to allow us to share your data. If we have your permission, we will share your information only with other organisations stated. We may share your data with our dedicated Member Service providers (Club Care Insurance, RAC Arrival, Club Autosave, Club Secure) this is so they are able to administer their services to you. 

The Club's election process also requires us to share your data with a third party, MI-Voice, who manages elections on our behalf. The purpose is solely for the administration of the election and data is deleted 3 months after this process is completed.

The Club prides itself on listening to its members and from time-to-time will conduct research to consult members and ask opinions, this could be conducted by the Club or by a carefully selected third party company. When using a third party company, member’s data will only be used for this purpose and once the research project is completed all data will be deleted. 

### Legal information and how to contact us

The data controller is the organisation responsible for protecting information and, in our case, is The Camping and Caravanning Club, Greenfields House, Westwood Way, Coventry, CV4 8JH.

If you would like access to, or a copy of, the personal information we hold about you; to request a correction; or have any questions about how we may use it; or to make a complaint, please contact the Data Protection Manager at the address shown above. Or, [email us](mailto:info@thefriendlyclub.co.uk). 

Complaints will be dealt with by the Data Protection Manager, and will be responded to within 30 days at the latest.

If you are not satisfied with the way your complaint was handled, you may be able to refer your complaint to your local data protection regulator. As the Club is based in the United Kingdom this is the ICO (Information Commissioner's Office).

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

Should we elect to change our Privacy Policy we will post the changes here. Where the changes are significant, we may also choose to email our members/users with the new details. 

Last updated on Wednesday 28 June 2017 14:35
